<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John T Kristoff on John T Kristoff</title>
    <link>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in John T Kristoff on John T Kristoff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 John T Kristoff</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>REN-ISAC DNS over TCP survey</title>
      <link>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/post/ri-dnstcp-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/post/ri-dnstcp-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April of this year I conducted an informal two-question survey aimed
at the general membership population of the &lt;a href=&#34;//ren-isac.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;REN-ISAC&lt;/a&gt;
community.  The intent was to gather personal positions and associated
member institution stances on DNS over TCP (i.e. should it be filtered,
restricted, or unfettered).  I was interested in gathering Internet
community perceptions after a recently submitted &lt;a href=&#34;//tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-dnsop-dns-tcp-requirements&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Internet-Draft on DNS
Transport over
TCP&lt;/a&gt; was
adopted by the IETF dnsop working group.  REN-ISAC participants are
generally well regarded, having both a breadth of knowledge and above
average technical expertise.  I had hoped the results would demonstrate
the &amp;ldquo;best case&amp;rdquo; representation of any organized security community.  By
best case, I mean those who realize the pitfalls of filtering or
restricting DNS over TCP traffic, and who would generally accept that it
ought to be allowed unfettered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey was conducted online, solicited through an email link that
reached all subscribed members, of which there were approximately 1700
at the time.  The survey link was available for approximately one week.
A little over 60 people responded, for a return rate of approximately
3.5%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were only two survey questions, both with three answer choices
each.  Only one answer per question was allowed.  The questions and
their respective answer choices are shown below.  Following each answer
choice in bold are the representative tallies of the voting results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question I&lt;/strong&gt;: Which statement most closely reflects your current
thinking on the role, use, and handling of DNS over TCP traffic on
the Internet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should be blocked everywhere / it is unnecessary or unwanted.
&lt;strong&gt;[6%]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should be restricted in use to DNS zone transfers between
authorized hosts only (i.e. masters and slaves). &lt;strong&gt;[38%]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should be allowed wherever DNS communications are permitted.
&lt;strong&gt;[56%]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question II&lt;/strong&gt;: Which statement most closely reflects how your
institution treats DNS over TCP traffic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is allowed wherever DNS communications are permitted.
&lt;strong&gt;[79%]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is restricted in use to DNS zone transfers between authorized
hosts only (i.e. masters and slaves). &lt;strong&gt;[18%]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is blocked everywhere / it is unnecessary or unwanted.
&lt;strong&gt;[3%]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results weren&amp;rsquo;t too surprising, at least not to me.  If I were to
have guessed ahead of time, I might have overestimated the population of
those who have a desire to block DNS over TCP everywhere.  Perhaps the
results reflect a bias of the the research and education (R&amp;amp;E)
community, which historically leans toward the less restrictive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth pointing out the difference in answers between the two
questions.  What the institution does and what the person answering
prefers shows that a significant number of respondents would be more
restrictive than what occurs in practice.  This difference is likely
attributable in part to the type of respondent polled.   REN-ISAC
members are primarily information security staff.  Security personnel
probably tend to skew towards a default deny stance more than their
colleagues in other departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could affect any sort of change in attitude and practice, it would
be to enlighten those who mistakenly believe DNS over TCP is only ever
used for zone transfers or to convince those who might limit DNS over
TCP for any reason to reconsider.  With any luck, the IETF document I&amp;rsquo;m
working on well help do just that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS Transport over TCP - Operational Requirements</title>
      <link>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/publication/draft-ietf-dnsop-dns-tcp-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/publication/draft-ietf-dnsop-dns-tcp-requirements/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS Transport over TCP Operational Requirements</title>
      <link>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/talk/ietf98-dnstcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/talk/ietf98-dnstcp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Potential Abuse of IGMP</title>
      <link>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/publication/on-the-potential-abuse-of-igmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/publication/on-the-potential-abuse-of-igmp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DePaul University Wireless</title>
      <link>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/talk/dpu2016-wireless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aharp.iorc.depaul.edu/talk/dpu2016-wireless/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
